As AI is getting better at writing
front-end code, your only choice to stay
relevant and competitive as a front-end
engineer is to level up your system
design and architecture skills. The
problem is that most system design
content is way too focused on the
back-end while completely ignoring the
front-end. So today I'm going to break
down every front-end system design
concept you need to know from
micro-front-ends architectures to system
design patterns like back-end for
front-end and then go into mono-repos
and rendering strategies like
server-side rendering. I'll also show
you what is the best way to use AI and
agentic coding to deploy these systems
to production. Now let's start with our
first front-end system design concept,
micro-front-ends. Now the traditional
front-end application will start as a
front-end monolith. That means pretty
much everything is in the same place.
And when it comes to micro-front-ends,
it basically means that we will split
this application into independent
front-end applications and then put them
all together. But before we even talk
about micro-front-ends, we need to
understand microservices and that is a
back-end architecture style. And so
looking at our client-server model, both
the server and the client will be
monoliths. That is single applications.
And at that point we keep adding
features to it because you're in the
initial phase of the project. But as you
scale, more and more people will have to
work on the same code base and your
development team becomes huge. And I've
worked with developers that told me
their development team was 40 people and
their daily stand-up took 1 hour and a
half just for everybody to speak for 1
minute and a half. And that's just not
sustainable. So that's where
microservices and micro-front-ends come
into place because this kind of
architecture doesn't scale from a
development point of view. Now you've
probably heard about the term two pizzas
team where Jeff Bezos said that team
shouldn't be bigger than five to nine
people, which is as many as you can feed
with one pizza. Now the two pizzas team
becomes a one pizza team with AI.
Because nowadays you can do the same
work with a lot less people using
agentic coding. And so, the ideal size
of the team becomes smaller and smaller.
Now, do remember that even if coding
agents like Cloud Code drive
implementation time to zero, they do
increase the verification time. So,
being an AI savvy front-end engineers it
means you design system that decrease
the verification time and minimize
architectural drift while they maximize
velocity. And so, it's not anymore about
implementing fast, but rather building a
system that is extremely easy to verify.
And we'll see how that changes
architecture later on. But, keep this
principle in mind. And so, in the ideal
case we are able to split our monolithic
team into feature teams that own a
specific feature. And those teams are
full stack and they work with coding
agents, but they can deliver
independently and that's how we can keep
our product moving forward. And so,
we'll have these different feature
teams, but it's also shared
infrastructure and that's owned by the
platform team. You might have front-end
tooling or pure infrastructures like the
servers. So, you might have a team for
example that is building a design system
that the feature teams are using. And
all those teams are smaller and they all
work with coding agents. That is the new
norm in development teams. Now,
according to Conway's law, the software
architecture of a system will look like
the organization of the people. So, if
what we want is smaller independent
teams, then we need to somehow break our
system into small independent vertical
slices. And this truly starts in the
back-end where we take our monolith and
we split out the independent modules to
build microservices. Those are
independent small back-ends, micro
back-ends that expose their own API and
can be deployed independently. The code
base is independent and you have
independent teams that don't need to
talk to each other extending those and
they only communicate between each other
through APIs. And so, a typical
microservice blueprint will look like
something like this. We have an API,
there's a business logic layer, then
there's a persistence layer and usually
a database. In this case I added a
Postgres DB, but it could be a no sequel
DB. And so, this is the building unit of
your application, and big applications
will have thousands of those in
productions. A couple of years ago, I
used to work for this financial company,
and we had around 1,000 microservices in
production, and you had different teams
only different microservices. My team
owned 13 of them. And by the way, if you
want to see where do you stand across
the full stack, there's a free
assessment that you can take in the link
below, and you basically understand how
much of this full stack knowledge you
actually have, where is the gap, and we
added a new AI section because a lot of
companies are starting to ask AI
questions in front-end engineering
interviews, also. So, take the
assessment and you can see more or less
where do you stand in the market and
what gaps you need to close. Link it's
in the comments. Now, moving on, we
split our back end into microservices,
but our front end is still a monolith.
So, even if our back end teams now could
ship independently and be much smaller
and go much faster, the front end is
pretty much the same. And the problem
with the front end is that you have so
many people pushing code to the same
client that it's so easy for someone to
make a mistake or bring the whole system
down or change a global CSS rule that
then affects everybody. So, as of now,
our front end team is still very, very
big and totally not sustainable. It gets
to a point where we just cannot scale
because there's just too much
communication overhead between all those
people needing to coordinate as they
work on the same code base. And that's
why we go back to micro front ends,
where we have a front end monolith and
we split it in different independent
front end applications. Now, how do we
put all those together? Well, basically,
we'll have a shell. And the micro front
end shell is the one that takes care of
the global functionality, things like
auth, routing, language, global state,
you know, are the users logged in or
not, it's all handled by that. And all
the others model applications, they live
inside this one. They're basically
loaded by this micro front end shell.
And this micro front end shell, it's
also on passing this global state inside
those micro front ends. But remember,
those applications are now deployable
independently. That means you might have
a domain that it's
header.theseniordev.com,
where, for example, we would host only
our header application, and you could
load that independently. And then you
have the product page and the cart page,
but then you have the shell that puts
them all together. So, if you look at a
big software company like amazon.com,
you could basically split the header,
and then maybe take out the product page
and the payment into two different micro
front-ends. But, to be honest, I feel
like they have even more granularity
there, and they probably split their
front-ends into even smaller and more
focused micro front-ends. So, once you
apply micro front-ends and microservices
together, you end up with a micro
front-end that will speak to one or
several microservices in the same
domain. And this is what we call a
vertical slice. And this system can now
be extended by an independent team. So,
we can start releasing changes
independently. Our releases are not a
bottleneck for another team, and we can
work against the APIs of other teams.
This is how pretty much every big
software company operates. And this is
what in software architecture they call
vertical slicing, where your features
are vertically owned by one team. And
I'm going to go even farther and tell
you that if you are an engineer, and
you're doing only front-end or back-end,
you have to move as fast as you can
towards becoming a vertically integrated
engineer, basically a team of one that
can work with a coding agent across the
full stack. And we'll see in a second
why that happens. But, that's the
transition you're going to need to go
through to survive in today's market.
So, when it comes to traditional
front-end engineering and front-end
development, we see that moving towards
two extremes, where you're either more
of a full-stack person that works in a
feature team, so they work across these
vertical slices, and that's why you need
to know a bit more about full-stack. By
the way, we do have full-stack videos on
this channel. If you want to know, as a
front-end engineer, transition slowly
towards a full-stack. Or, you're going
to be really good at the front-end, and
then you're going to the infra team, and
you start building it at the shell, or
you build a design system, and that's
where you do spend a lot of time, you
know, doing traditional front-end work
with just CSS, and building the building
blocks that the feature teams will
implement. And pretty much both of those
people will work with coding agents.
Now, a quick tip about AI and AI coding,
micro front-ends and microservices
decrease the blast radius of a
production bug, and they could use the
cognitive load of code changes because
you have smaller and localized PRs. You
also get less context, which means your
AI coding tool would be much more
efficient because you work on smaller
pieces and the risk is less. So, it's a
really good strategy when you have a lot
of people pushing a lot of code very
frequently as we do with AI to move
towards micro front-ends and
microservices because the risk is lower
and it decrease what we call the
verification time. It's just easier to
go on the quality when the surface area
of the changes you are making is
smaller. So, micro front-ends and
microservices are usually the way to go
if you're building fast with AI. Now,
let's move to our next concept, which is
only API gateway. Now, whenever we have
a micro front-end and a back-end
service, we need to end up making a lot
of requests. And those requests have
what we call edge functions. They need
caching, HTTPS, authentication, content
negotiation, rate limiting for security,
and so all this functionality at the API
level it's pretty repetitive. So, having
to implement this both on the front-end
side and on the back-end side every time
we plug in a new microservice to the
micro front-end ends up adding a lot of
overhead. And it becomes a lot harder to
do this if you have a lot of back-end
services. So, a typical solution is to
add what we call an API gateway, and
that would be your gate into the
back-end systems. And the advantage of
an API gateway is that the client would
only implement the edge functions once.
So, they basically only implement the
HTTPS handshake once, or caching, or
rate limiting, and then once the request
goes to the API gateway, it gets
forwarded to the back-end services,
which don't have to care about all this
functionality. They can just care about
their own logic. And all this usually
lives in a virtual private cloud, which
means it's totally secure because the
only way to go into it is through the
API gateway. The other cool feature when
you have an API gateway is that you can
make the communication between the
client and API gateway HTTPS, but the
communication between the microservices
and the API gateway HTTP because you
don't need that security anymore cuz
you're in a closed environment. And the
advantage here is performance because
HTTPS it's likely less performant than
the HTTP because you need more round
trips to do the HTTPS handshake. So, in
general, once you have a couple of
microservices in production, it's a good
idea to add an API gateway both for
security and performance and also less
complexity in the front end. Now, let's
move on to our next pattern, very
similar to the API gateway, we have the
backend for frontend. Now, let's
remember our setup from before where we
have our client and our API gateway and
all our microservices. The problem here
is that the client has to make a call to
all these different microservices that
might have a different API and there's
so many fetch calls. And if you're in
the frontend team, whenever you need a
new feature that needs even the
slightest backend change, you need to go
and talk to that backend team and figure
out if that will be a priority for them,
add it to their backlog, and maybe
something gets done. So, it ends up
being very, very slow. And one of the
biggest challenge that some of the
engineers we work with at the senior dev
that work in bigger companies is that
it's so hard for them to get things done
because they have to talk to key
different backend teams that have their
own backlog and their own priority. So,
they just don't want to implement that
small API field that they need. So,
better solution is to somehow own your
backend as a frontend team, as a client
team. There's also a lot of complexity
when you have to implement all these
different APIs because they all look
different, you need a different client
and SDK for all these different APIs.
And so, that's more frontend complexity.
So, the solution for that is to add what
we call a backend for frontend. This is
a backend that will take the frontend
request and then just forward it to the
microservices. But the advantage here is
that whenever you have to implement a
feature, you can act as a full-stack
developer when you're in the front-end
team. So, basically, you have all those
microservices, you integrate, like to
change the way you equals them from the
back-end for front-end, and then you
implement your feature, and you kind of
own end-to-end the client-side feature.
And the back-end teams, they can just
work in isolation on the different
microservices. So, the front-end team
ends up owning both the client and the
back-end for front-end, and back-end
teams they develop pure back-end
services. And this is very important for
you as a front-end engineer because it
means that you do need to know, at least
at the high level, how to extend a
microservice, how to build a back-end
for front-end. You need to know API
design, and you need to know a little
bit about GraphQL, for example, which is
a great technology to build back-end for
front-ends. This is a requirement for
all the front-end engineers that you see
working at bigger companies, which are
usually the ones that also have the best
conditions and the most exciting work.
So, even if you're in the front-end,
make sure that you can also get things
done in the back-end. Now, the advantage
with BFFs is that you can adapt them to
a specific client. So, if in the future
we end up building a mobile app that has
totally different requirements to our
desktop app, we don't need to duplicate
API endpoints. So, with back-end for
front-ends, every client will have its
own dedicated back-end, which means
every client team can work independently
and is completely decoupled from the
back-end services that can just focus on
their own service. And so, basically,
whenever the desktop client, for
example, goes to gateway, they get
redirected to the desktop back-end for
front-end. And for mobile, we have a
completely different API, a completely
different mobile back-end for front-end.
It uses the same back-end services, but
it might expose a total different API to
consume them, just because the data
needs in mobile are usually different
from desktop. Where in desktop, you want
to fetch a lot of information at once,
but in mobiles, we have smaller screens,
so you need different records. And if
you try to put all those things together
in a single API, it will become bloated,
or it will end up not satisfying one of
the requests. For example, you'll have a
great API for desktop, but when it comes
to mobile, you'll fetch too much data, a
lot of data you don't really need
because the interface is a bit
different. Or if you make the smaller
endpoints, when it comes to desktop,
you'll have to make many requests to get
the same data. So, you'll have
over-fetching or under-fetching, and
it's a lot better if you split those
things. On to the next concept, which is
load balancing. Now, going back to our
client-server model, we had a server and
we end up having clients. But, the
problem is we might get a lot of users.
And so, you have all those clients
making requests to a single server. Now,
a typical Node.js server is pretty
powerful. It can usually satisfy up to
2,000 to 10,000 concurrent requests with
a well-optimized Node.js server. But,
when you go beyond that, you might need
different ways to scale it because a
single server has its own limits. And
the easiest way to scale it is by load
balancing. And that means you basically
will create identical instances of your
servers and then have this component
that's an application load balancer
splitting traffic between them. Now,
load balancing is a topic by itself.
There's different ways to split traffic
and different criterias. And as a
front-end engineer, you don't need to go
so deep into it. But, do make sure that
you know about it. Ideally, you're even
capable of setting up a small load
balancer using traditional web servers
like Nginx and Docker Compose, you can
have this set up on your local machine.
Anyhow, the important thing is that you
can reason your way through it. Most
cloud providers like AWS or Google
Cloud, they allow you to provision a
load balancer in seconds. So, don't
worry about it. It's very uncommon that
you need to manually set up one, but
it's important that you know about it.
Now, congrats on making it this far.
Make sure you subscribe so you don't
lose any updates in the future, and
let's move on to our next concept, which
is container systems. So, we basically
distributed our architecture into micro
front-ends and different microservices,
but the problem is that deploying all
this would be a headache. Now we need to
build up and provision infrastructure
and pipelines, and they all might use
different technologies. You might have a
Python microservice and then a Node.js
one. You might have a Vue.js application
or a Next.js application. And this is
all very complicated to get to
production. So, in order to standardize
the deployment, we can actually use
Docker. And Docker is technology that
allows you to package your application
to Docker image. And the way you do that
is that you take your code, and then you
have a Dockerfile where you kind of
declare your recipe of how we should
package that code. And basically, based
on that, you'll create a Docker image.
The Docker image will contain all the
application code and then the runtime.
Let's imagine you're using Next.js, then
it will contain Next.js, will have the
runtime, which is Node, and then the
operating system, which is usually
Linux. And that is a full Docker image,
and the advantage there is that whenever
you find a host that runs Docker, you
can run that image. You don't need to
worry about the Node.js version or if
they need to install PHP and all the
dependencies that your application has.
It really comes packaged all together.
This is Docker image. You run it, open
this port, you have a front end running.
You don't need to know about what's
inside. And this is wonderful for DevOps
teams because all of the sudden they can
take all those images and push them into
a container orchestration system. A
container orchestration system usually
has a container deployment pipeline,
which will run these containers. And so,
running a container is not as easy as it
sounds. You might need load balancing.
Uh you might want to run several
instances in parallel and be able to,
you know, if a container fails, spin up
another one really fast. So, all this
kind of hard work it's built into
systems like Kubernetes. You probably
saw it in job office. Now, do you need
to know Kubernetes as a front end
engineer? No. But you do need to
explain, you do need to know about it,
and you will see a lot of front end
positions that mention either Kubernetes
or container systems or a ECS, which is
the AWS alternative to Kubernetes, in
the job description. Don't be scared.
You don't need to become a DevOps
engineer by tomorrow, but you should be
able to, at a high level, understand
where it fits in your architecture.
Finally, a more front-end concept, a
CDN, a content delivery network. So,
what is a CDN? So, going back to a
client-server model, imagine you are a
client, you want to go on a website, you
usually go to the server and get some
static files. Static JavaScript and CSS,
and you download that and you run that
on your web browser. Let's imagine in a
more hypothetical case that you are a
user from the US and you want to visit
the application that is based in Europe.
For you to get the JavaScript and CSS
and all the HTML, you have to go all the
way to the Atlantic Ocean and come back.
And that young trip adds latency, and
there's no physical way you can work
around it. No matter how performant your
application is, there is the limit of
the speed of light, because data only
travels as fast as the speed of light,
and over long distances, light is very
fast, but it still will add around,
let's say, 200 ms to 250 ms on every
request of latency. So, a solution to
that is to your client decrease the
distance between you and where those
files are hosted. And the easiest way is
to use a content delivery network. And
so, basically, a CDN will be a network
of these edge locations that are placed
all over the world, and what happens is
that the server will push the static
assets there, and whenever you make a
request, you'll be redirected to the
edge location that is closest to you.
Now, this mechanism on how exactly are
you getting redirected to that edge
location that is closest to you, it's
very interesting, and I do want to make
a video about it, but I'm not sure if
it's something you're interested in. If
you want a video about it, let me know
in the comments. It's a bit more
technical, and it's not something you'll
get in interviews. But, to be honest,
it's really interesting. So, if you want
me to make a video about it, just give
me an excuse by letting me know in the
comments, and I'll go ahead and do that.
Now, a CDN is a distributed cache. So,
the technical term for whenever you get
the asset from the CDN, it's a cache
hit. And whenever the server pushes a
new version, that's called cache
invalidation. And this concept is very
closely related to what we call cache
busting, which is a mechanism that
module bundles use to invalidate your
assets. So, we make sure that when you
deploy a new version, users really get
the latest one, not a previous version
that is probably still sitting somewhere
in the CDN. I do have other videos in
the channel talking about it, so I'm not
going to go deep into it. But make sure
you're able to relate those things
across the stack. Now, keep in mind that
a CDN is the fastest and most
cost-effective to increase web
performance by serving optimized assets
with the right cache policy out of the
box. Because nowadays, CDNs do a lot
more than just placing the asset close
to the client. They also compress it,
and they also take care of the caching
policy. So, it's a really cheap way for
you to fix most performance problems.
Now, let's talk about design systems.
And going back to our micro front-end
discussions, we have a feature team,
that's a product feature team, and then
we might have the payments feature team,
and they work separately and release
independently. Those are completely
separate product teams. And the problem
there is that you might get code
repetition or what we call visual
divergence. You can have this silos
mentality. And so, basically, a button
in the product page will look
differently than a button on the payment
page. And so, you will lose what we call
visual coherence, and people will start
to notice that those are actually
separate front-ends because they look
differently. And that's not good from a
product perspective, but it's also not
good from a technical perspective
because you have too much repeated code.
And so, the solution is to have a design
system. And in a design system, the
first thing you do is to define your
design tokens. That's basically your
team information. What's your primary
color, what is your border definition,
your fonts families, and so on and so
forth. And the modern way to do that is
you add them as CSS custom properties,
basically variables, at the global level
in your CSS, probably in the shell micro
front end, and then it gets fed into all
the other micro front ends. But, you can
go a bit farther and build reusable
components that then the feature teams
can use to assemble their features. So,
you could build inputs and buttons, and
basically they would consume that UI
package and use it in all these
different micro front ends. So,
basically what you achieve is that the
UI looks consistent, but also you don't
repeat your code. The cool thing about
the design system is you can take care
of accessibility, you can have all those
components unit tested, and basically
you are applying at an architectural
level the do not repeat yourself dry
principle. And going back to AI coding,
a solid design system really makes the
difference between generating some
component slob and having inconsistent
styles and bugs that need a lot of
rework, and really having a consistent,
reliable coding agent output. Trust me,
I've been building a lot of AI in the
last couple of months, and the first
thing I do when I make a new project is
to tell to extract from whatever the
design is the design system, because
then you feed that into your coding
agent through different sessions, and
you still get consistent output. If you
don't do that, the agent will make
things up, and your UI would just look
different, and it'll be obvious that it
was live coded. Now, our next concept is
a design to code MCP, that's a model
context protocol server. And so,
basically, you remember we have our
design system, and normally you would
import that to start building with it.
But, nowadays, let's imagine that your
designers built your design system
initially in Figma, and then you
implement it in your library. You can
use the Figma MCP server with a coding
agent to very quickly assemble features
into the feature teams, into the
vertical slices of your product. And
this is the kind of workflow that most
companies are moving towards. So, if you
are a front end engineer, you got to
make sure that you know how to use an
MCP server, you know what an MCP server
is, and ideally, whatever design tool
your team is using, you can plug an MCP
into that or you might have to even
build that connection yourself. And then
plug that into your AI coding agent like
Cloud Code, which is the most used in
enterprise or Codex. Now, a quick note
on CSS architecture and design tokens.
What you can do to take things even
further is to apply the Atomic CSS
methodology and with your design tokens,
create atomic classes that you can use
in your code base. So, basically, you
define what the border would be, but
then you create a dot border class that
has that property. And then the only
thing that other developers have to do
is to use that class. And this is how
Tailwind CSS works. So, keep this in
mind. Tailwind CSS is an implementation
of the Atomic CSS architecture style for
CSS. And there's three more
architectural styles, which I won't get
into right now, but who knows, maybe
I'll make a video about it later on.
Next front end system design concept,
the monorepo. So, basically, our
applications right now are sitting in
all these different repos where you have
a GitHub repo for the shell, one for the
payment micro front end, inventory micro
front end, and it's all spread out into
thousands of repos. And the problem
there is that you end up with different
code styles, different dependencies, and
different quality standards. Some people
might be using TypeScript, they might be
using different linter configurations,
and it's so easy to have what we call
architectural drift or code style drift
where two projects diverge too much.
What's the problem with that? If you're
a developer and you change teams, you
have to relearn everything. So, you
don't really leverage standardization.
And the way to is to put everything into
a single repository. So, basically, you
have a big repository that contains all
the other small applications, and you
have tooling that works with both of
them. So, for example, when you run NPM
run build in a monorepo, all your
applications will build individually.
Now, when it comes to AI coding, a
monorepo gives coding agents the context
they need to make changes across service
boundaries. So, for example, if you're
building a micro front and you realize
that you run into a reusable use case.
You can easily extract that and propose
it as a component into your design
system. That might be a different repo.
And you can do that with the coding
agent in a single session if you have
everything in a mono repo. If not, you
have to somehow feed those two different
repositories to your coding agent and
everything becomes harder. So, combining
micro frontends and microservices with a
mono repo, it's usually the most
efficient way to work with AI. Now, one
thing I'm really excited about is also
MC PUI. So, MC PUI is basically
combining the traditional website with
an LLM-powered app, and that's basically
the glue in between them, the duct tape,
let's say that. And so, basically, in a
chat application, you usually send a
chat query, and then that goes to the
LLM, and the LLM will answer back, but
in this case, it can actually answer
with UI components. It can actually
render products, for example, in the
answer, not only text. But to do that,
it has to somehow talk to the backend,
and then we need to render some
components. And that is what MC PUI
solves. And this is an example I found
in a recent website where I was looking
for venues for events because we are
organizing our annual in-person meetups
at the Senior Dev, so we're going to
meet all the engineers we work with
around Europe or in the US, and I was
looking for different cool venues where
we could actually meet up. And so, I was
talking to this chat UI, and all of a
sudden, after a couple of questions, it
started rendering those venues, and it's
asking me for input, and then it would
go into a deep search and give me even
more venues. And as you see there, it
can even render a map. And all this
happens in a chat application. And I
think this is the direction front end
will go with LLMs, where we will
integrate LLMs in web applications would
be. A lot of people were saying that
there's no more need for UI now that we
have a chat. I disagree. I think the UI
is a very useful way to communicate
things, and I think you need front end
developers, but we'll be able to combine
the LLM approach with the traditional
web approach. So, this component was
rendered because the front end parsed it
from the answers of the LLM. At a high
level, the way this works is that the
model harness will provide in the
context the tool registries and all the
MCP servers and then as a user prompt,
and the LLM will send an answer back to
the tool UI with the text answer, but
also with an instruction to render a
certain div, and then the tool, the web
application has to follow that and
render it.
And just to really bring this to the
code, the way we declare a resource or
an MCP UI is we basically tell the LLM,
"Hey, there's this resource, and you can
use it in this case scenario, and this
is the answer you can give." And then
our front end has to take that and parse
that and then render it. If you want me
to make an in-depth video on how exactly
MCP UI works, let me know, but this is
one of those patterns that if you know
really well, you'll really stand out
because I believe it goes way beyond the
current AI hype and it's actually
something very useful for specific edge
cases, and you'll see a lot of
applications actually implementing this
hybrid solutions. Now, to wrap up this
talk a bit about performance, and the
most important pattern that you'll ever
see out mentioned in job descriptions
for front end engineers, it's the Core
Web Vitals. And so basically the Core
Web Vitals are three metrics that
quantify the three dimensions in which
we measure the performance of a website,
and those are the loading speed, the
interactivity speed, and the visual
stability. And the three Core Web Vitals
that measure this are the Largest
Contentful Paint, the Interaction to
Next Paint, and the Cumulative Layout
Shift. Basically, those are measured by
Google, and they tell us what a good
number would be. So, when you look at
the Largest Contentful Paint, it would
be the time it takes from when you hit
enter to when the largest element in the
web page is rendered. The Interaction to
Next Paint, it's slightly different, and
it has to do to when you interact. So,
you do something, and then when do we
repaint the UI? And the CLS is basically
how much the UI changes when it loads.
And so, the LCP and CLS have to do with
the initial render, and the INP has to
do with the re-renderings, which is very
important when you talk about component
frameworks. Now, to understand those,
you need to understand the critical
rendering path, which is all the steps
you go from downloading some HTML to
actually showing something on the
screen. And that involves building the
DOM, and then building the CSSOM, then
building a render tree, then computing
the layout tree, which is basically a
tree of where all your nodes are and the
positions and the width, and then
transforming that into what we call
paint operations that goes through to
the GPU, then going to the composite
phase, which has its own complexity, and
I'm not going to talk about it, but just
to summarize this, all those steps will
happen, and then you have some
re-renders because we use component
frameworks, you get data, you start
re-rendering, you finally finish, and
then that's when you paint the LCP. So,
all that time is measured in the LCP,
and the bottom line here is, if you're
shipping a lot of JavaScript, if you're
shipping a lot of CSS, if you have to
fetch a lot of data, and your server is
slow, your application will be slow, and
you'll get a very poor score in the LCP.
The other thing that will happen if your
application is poorly optimized is that
you'll have layout switching all the
time as you start loading things because
CSS comes too late, and then fonts come
in, and then some data comes in, and the
browser will take screenshots of that
and try to figure out if you are moving
things too much. That would be the
cumulative layout shift. And finally,
the interaction to next paint is
basically whenever you have a user
event, and you have to go to the
reconciliation and re-render after state
update in your framework, and then you
start again, you modify the DOM, and
that triggers a re-paint. So, all that
time it's quantified as the interaction
to next paint. So, basically, if you
have very slow re-renders or you're
re-rendering too many components when
users do something, then you have a very
slow IMP. You can measure those metrics
like house, and they go a lot deeper
into this video on this channel about
it, so make sure you check out that one.
Our next concept also has to do with
performance, and it's called splitting.
Now, traditionally, a module bundler
will take all our JavaScript and put it
together in a single big file. But
loading that single file will totally
mess our core web vitals because we load
too much JavaScript. So code splitting
allows us to split our JavaScript to
where it's being needed so we can really
ship only the JavaScript that's needed
to a specific page. And the easiest way
to code split is by out. So basically,
you would only ship to the slash login
page the components that are
specifically needed for the login. And
if you have a dashboard that's very
heavy with a lot of graphs, for example,
you don't ship all that. So you
selectively ship your JavaScript to
where it's being needed instead of
putting it together all in a single
file. And all this is achieved with a
module bundler like Webpack or Vit,
which understands your bundle, splits
it, and then dynamically loads it based
on the path you're on, working together
with your application router. And the
higher overarching mental model here is
lazy loading, which is the opposite of
eager loading. Eager loading means you
are really loading everything when a
user lands on the page. And lazy loading
means you load things as they needed. So
for example, you might load certain
things on scroll, or you might load
certain things when they visit a certain
page, or you might load certain things
when they click on something. So you
kind of wait for that user interaction,
and when they land on the page, you
really only ship the things they need.
And all this is done in order to make
this core web vitals better and working
across the critical learning path. And
finally, let's talk about rendering
strategies. And nowadays, we usually
work with modern component frameworks
like React, Vue, and Angular. And the
problem with those is that when you land
on the page, you see a white screen. And
the reason for that is because, you
know, you load that empty HTML, and
until you don't really run whatever
render function they have, you don't
really see much on the screen. That's
what they call client-side rendering. So
in an SPA architecture, in a single-page
application with client-side rendering,
you'd go, get your static file, and then
you need to go get some dynamic data,
and then finally render. And all that
takes a lot of time. So, if you want to
have a very performant website or a
website that's ready to be crawled by a
search engine, then client-side
rendering is not the best choice for
you. An alternative to this, if you have
a static website where there's not a lot
of interactivity, is to pre-render it on
the server and ship it already rendered.
So, when your client goes to get the
static files, they already get HTML CSS
and they don't need to run so much
JavaScript. Now, again, this only works
with static sites. If your static site
will change often, let's say you have a
blog and you want to publish new
articles, then what you can do is
incremental static generation. That
means you only regenerate the pages that
have changed. So, basically, your CMS
will trigger a rebuild when you add a
new blog post and that will get the
dynamic data and go to a build pipeline
and regenerate the only portion of the
static files that change. So, it's a bit
of a partial rebuilding of the website.
The advantage here is not only that
makes the build faster, but if I'm a
client and I already downloaded part of
your CSS and JavaScript, but I don't
need to download re-download only the
parts that change. Now, in most cases,
this is built into a framework like
Next.js, so you never have to worry
about this yourself. And finally, we
have server-side rendering. And in
server-side rendering, the client will
make a request to the front-end server,
but then the front-end server will
request the back-end server and get some
data and then render the application on
the server and then send it back
pre-rendered. So, the client receives a
full HTML page. So, you don't have this
problem of the white screen. The problem
you still have is that this page is not
interactive yet because you haven't went
through building the virtual DOM and
attaching, for example, in the case of
React, your virtual DOM to the actual
DOM pre-built. And that's why you need
to hydrate. And so, basically, you
render that HTML page and then you have
to execute your JavaScript, create
internally the virtual DOM and then that
virtual DOM is attached to the existing
HTML markdown. That's what we call
hydration. And finally, when you're
hydrated, you might have to do some
extra data fetching, so you might still
need to go to the back. And again, this
is one of the most complex approaches,
so be careful with it. It's only useful
whenever you need very, very fast
performance or you need SEO. And a lot
of people and a lot of companies jumped
into this and they're doing server-side
rendering, but that's like building an
F1 car to go to the groceries. It's
over-engineering and it creates a lot of
problems and then everything gets
slower. There's so many issues that will
appear when you have this kind of setup.
Technology to make it work is very
complex. Bugs are harder to solve, so
you want to stay away from it. And I
really prefer simple solutions unless
your use case really needs the highest
performance. Oh, finally, let's talk
about data fetching and I know we are
front-end engineers, but it's very
important that you also can work at a
data layer. As I said before, we are
moving towards front-end engineers being
more full stack. And that is server-sent
events. And all this has to do with
real-time communication. When it comes
to real-time communication that is not
following the request-response cycle
that I showed until now, you basically
have to give it to it. You can do
polling, you can do web sockets or
server-sent events. And so polling would
mean that you keep calling a specific
endpoint until something happens. So,
let's say we have a transaction that's
processing, I can keep calling the
status endpoint until it becomes
completed. That's very easy to do with
plain JavaScript and set timeout.
There's nothing complex about it. The
problem is you're calling your server
way too much. And so it doesn't scale
really well. You can have race
conditions. So, it's a very simple
solution, but not the most performant
one. The next alternative would be web
sockets, where you open a channel
between the server and the browser and
you can send updates and they can send
you updates back. The problem here is
that again, it's a lot of overhead and
it's extremely good whenever you have
bi-directional communication. Like
you're working for a chat application,
for example, where both the client and
the server would keep sending chunks of
messages. Now, for most use cases, this
is not really needed and again, it's
complex and it's very intense on the
server. It needs a lot of resources.
Now, with AI, we do need real-time
communication, but it's only one
direction. Because usually when you send
a query to a chat application, you then
just wait and they start sending you
tokens back. So, it's the server sending
a lot of messages, but you usually only
send one. So, there's a lot of asymmetry
between the client and the server. And
the way to make this happen is with
server-sent events, where you send a
text message and that will create a
conversation and on that endpoint,
you're able to receive updates from the
server. So, you receive all these
tokens, but you don't send so many. And
this approach is the one used by most
LLM applications. If you've ever used
the OpenAI NPM package in a React
application to build a chat app with an
LLM, that's exactly what they use under
the hood. And you can actually figure
this out if you go to your network when
you use ChatGPT or Claude and find that
conversation request and you'll see that
the answer to that it's all these event
streams. So, you're getting chunks of
the answer. And that's how you build
these cool UIs for LLMs. It's not
WebSockets and it's not pulling, it's
the server-sent event API. Make sure you
look it up because it is something that
will help you build product software
products, software applications with AI
embedded. Thanks so much, folks. If you
want to go even deeper, make sure you
check out these two videos on our
channel. One of them is about all the
front-end architectures that you need to
know as a front-end engineer and the
other one is about in-depth concepts
about web performance, CSS, component
frameworks that you really need and that
show up in interviews at the senior
level. And I'll see you in the next one.