You know him. Long ponytail, oval
glasses, has been at the company longer
than the version control. You show him
50 lines, he looks at them, says
nothing, and replaces them with one.
That is the epic description of this new
library called Ponytail, which I guess
is kind of relatable. We all know that
one 10x developer who matches that
description perfectly. But Ponytail is
actually a really cool tool. It makes
your AI coding agent think like the
laziest senior dev in the room. And
that's actually a compliment. So, in
this video, we'll take a look at
Ponytail, see how it works, and run some
fun demos to find out if this guy is
actually the real deal. It's going to be
a lot of fun. So, let's dive into it.
So, Ponytail's mission is simple. Keep
everything super concise. eliminate the
bloat AI agents usually produce and try
to come up with the leanest solution to
a problem it can possibly find. It's
kind of similar to Caveman, which was
the library that made AI coding agents
talk less, therefore spending less
tokens, which James also did a great
video on over here. So, the main idea
behind it is embracing the Yagy
principle, which stands for you ain't
going to need it. It's actually a
software engineering idea from the '9s.
And the core idea of it is don't build
something until you actually need it.
Don't add an abstraction layer. Don't
install a library. Don't write the
class. If the problem can be solved
without it, then just solve it without
it. And Ponytail bakes that directly
into your agent by giving it a decision
ladder it has to climb before writing
anything. Does this need to exist at
all? Can a standard library handle it?
Is there a native platform feature for
this? Is there already a dependency
installed that does this? Can it be a
oneliner? Only if every single one of
those answers is a no, then it actually
writes new code. And even then, it just
keeps it to the minimum required to get
it working. And if we look at some of
their examples, especially the modal
dialogue example, we get a clear picture
of this methodology. A normal agent when
asked to add a modal dialogue for the
delete confirmation will immediately
reach for installing a radex UI library
like the React dialogue and give you a
dependency and a portal, an overlay, a
root, a trigger, a content wrapper just
to show a box with two buttons. But
Ponytail looks at this and says, "Hey,
the browser already has a dialogue
element. It traps focus automatically
and it closes on escape, renders a
backdrop with a single CSS selector and
it's supported in every major browser
since 20122.
So instead of 30 lines in an MPM
package, you get eight lines and zero
dependencies. And this little ponytail
comment right here tells you exactly
what it skipped and why it did that. So
if one day you actually decide to
upgrade it to the radex version or
something more fancier, you know where
to go and where it was deferred. So it's
lazy, but it's not irresponsible. And by
embracing this laziness, Ponytail claims
to be able to reduce your cost by 47 to
77%. And they actually give some
benchmarks behind this claim. So let's
look at them for a moment. We have three
methods here. using no skill, using
caveman and using ponytail and three
models and five everyday tasks. 10 runs
per cell and for each of them the median
result. And crucially, they also check
for correctness. A broken oneliner that
scores great on lines of code will fail
on correctness. So it's not just write
less stuff, it has to actually work. And
there's also an interesting caveat worth
noting. cost reflects singleshot calls
that resend the skill every time. In
other words, the benchmark works by
sending a fresh API call for each test
and every time it does that, it includes
the full ponytail rule set in the
prompt. So in the benchmark, ponytail is
being penalized for the cost of its own
instructions on every single test. In
real life, you pay for those
instructions roughly once per session
and after that they are cashed. That
means the 47 to 77% cheaper figure is
actually underelling it. In a real
working session spread across many
prompts, the cost advantage is even
bigger because that skill injection cost
gets amvertised across the whole
conversation. That said, there is a
legitimate critique worth mentioning. A
recently published blog post by Colin
Eberhart points out that if you actually
swap out ponytail for three simple
words, follow Yagy principles, the
results of that almost perfectly matched
Ponytail's benchmark score. And when
elaborating to seven words, follow Yagy
principles and oneliner solutions, it
actually beat the benchmark. So is
ponytail magic or is it just a well
packaged prompt? Well, honestly, that is
a fair question, but I would argue that
packaging is the product. You get the
right rules injected automatically
across different agents with commands,
audit tools, and a debt ledger on top.
Besides, Ponytail has other cool
features. Follow Yagy in your system
prompt doesn't give you the ponytail
audit feature or the ponytail review
feature. But now, let's test it out with
a simple example. So here I have two
claude code instances open and on one of
them I'm going to install the ponytail
plugin for the local scope only and the
other one will be a simple default
claude code instance with no plugins
activated. I will give them both the
same prompt to build a weather dashboard
app that detects user location and shows
current weather conditions along with
some other features. And I'm going to
run the same prompt on both instances
with the only exception that on the
ponytail one I'm going to also ask it to
use the ponytail skill because sometimes
it doesn't automatically pick it up. So
after a few moments we see that ponytail
version has already finished the task in
under 1 minute while the default one is
still crunching. And also we see a very
concise overview of what it built and
what Ponytail opted out of doing for
maximum efficiency. And as we can see
here, it chose to have everything in one
single HTML file. Meanwhile, on the
default window, the task was finished in
2 minutes and 30 seconds. And we can
already see that this version is much
more bloated. We have three separate
files. And this version is run using a
Python server. So, while this isn't in
no means a bad result, it's much more
overengineered than the first version.
But let's actually look how they
operate. So, first off, this is the
version without ponytail. And while the
app looks great and the UI is beautiful
and the API retrieves information as
expected, I am quite disappointed that
it didn't pick up my location
automatically as I asked and instead it
shows me London as the default first
result. But now if we hop on to the
ponytail version here, we can clearly
see that upon opening it, it asks to get
my current location and then outputs the
weather matching that location instead.
So while the UI is maybe not as fancy
and the app is maybe more bare bones, it
did follow the instructions more
precisely than the default version,
which is quite surprising to be honest.
And lastly, let's look at the usage. And
here we can see that yes indeed the
version with ponytail ended up being 50%
cheaper than the default version and it
also produced far less lines of code.
And as we just saw it was even better in
terms of functionality than the default
version. So this proves that ponytail
does indeed work as expected and it does
produce leaner code. So since this test
was so successful, I decided to do
something even more interesting. What if
I combine Caveman and Ponytail together
for maximum efficiency? What will that
give us? So this time I activated both
plugins in a new directory and ran the
same prompt again. And once again the
task was finished under a minute and the
output was fairly similar and I had all
the same functionality. So it worked as
expected. But if we look at the output,
it didn't differ too much from the
ponytail version. And the caveman plus
ponytail combo ended up being even
slightly more expensive than the
standalone ponytail version. So this
shows that combining them doesn't really
give you any big improvement. So you can
stick to just using caveman or better
yet opted out for using ponytail if we
can believe their benchmarks that it is
indeed better than caveman. So there you
have it folks. That is ponytail in a
nutshell. I am honestly genuinely
impressed by the positive output Claude
was able to produce with the ponytail
skill while cutting the bloat and
maintaining the quality at the same
time. I guess this just goes to show
that a lot of our coding solutions are
probably overengineered and sometimes
less is indeed more if you use it the
right way. So, I'm definitely going to
be keeping Ponytail as a plug-in in my
Claude Code setup and probably use it
for future projects. But what do you
think about Ponytail? Have you tried it?
Will you use it? Let us know in the
comments section down below. And folks,
if you like these types of technical
breakdowns, please let me know by
smashing that like button underneath the
video. And also, don't forget to
subscribe to our channel. This has been
Andress from Better Stack, and I will
see you in the next videos. Heat.
Heat.