Google just announced something called
the Open Knowledge Format, and boy am I
excited about this. This is a whole new
layer for the internet. It's a way to
take your knowledge, your business
knowledge, your personal knowledge,
whatever it is, and structure it so that
agents can understand it. Now, this is
nothing new. The way that they do it is
they structure it in markdown files.
It's actually very, very simple. We'll
look at some examples in just a minute.
But, what is new is that it is a
standardized way of doing this. So that
if my agent wants to access your public
OKF, then
it can happen standardized. I don't need
to use any particular software to do it.
I could use something like Notion or
Obsidian to look at the markdown files.
I could ask my agent to make a web page
out of it. I could do all sorts of
things, but the key thing is that I have
access to the knowledge that a business
has chosen to provide. This is a really
big deal. I think it's going to change
how we do SEO. I think we're going to
need a different acronym. It's not SEO,
it's not GEO, it's not even agentic
search optimization. This isn't about
getting found, rather it is a way to
make your business accessible to agents.
Not just accessible, but make it so that
agents can do things with your business
knowledge. I do think that people who
understand OKF will be in high demand. I
think it's going to be a new service
that SEOs offer where kind of like
making a site map, but much more
detailed, where people will be really
good at understanding how to take a
business's knowledge and turn it into a
knowledge graph that is an OKF. But, I
think it's even more exciting for people
who actually have proprietary knowledge,
processes, or something that people
already pay you for, because you will be
able to, I'm fairly certain, I'm not I
don't know this 100% for sure, but you
should be able to sell your OKF bundles
and that way you can have access to an
expert's knowledge and even integrate it
into your own OKF. So that you will
have, you know, we'll probably buy OKF
bundles from a lawyer, from an
accountant, from an SEO. And I I think
this is a very very exciting thing. So
this is a proposed standard. It is just
the very first version and so if you're
watching this in the future, I'm
recording this mid-June. There probably
are some new versions that are out
there. I'd encourage you to do what I
did is take I've put some links in the
description for Google's documentation
on this and also the spec file in
GitHub. Put all of that into a Notebook
LM. Give that notebook to Gemini and
then ask Gemini to summarize the
information and tell you how you can use
this in your business. One good prompt
would say would be to say, "Give me 20
ideas of how I could use OKF in my
business." So let's get into Google's
description of what OKF is. OKF is a
specification that formalizes something
called the LLM Wiki pattern. This
pattern was described by Andre Karpathy.
We're going to look at that in just a
minute. But first let's look at what an
OKF is. It is just Markdown. If you're
not familiar with Markdown, it's just a
really simple way to describe text, you
know, as text. Uh
basically a text file that might have a
little bit of markup to say this is a
heading, this is bolded, or whatever.
Just a very simple way to understand
text. It is really easy for agents to
understand text. Now, we're not going to
be taking every page of our website and
turning that into a Markdown file. I
mean, we could. We're actually going to
take the things that we have on our
website, extract the concepts from
those, and make those concepts their own
Markdown files. Let's see if if can
explain that a little more clearly. I
found that this was the most helpful
document that Google produced. It's on
GitHub. Again, it's linked to in the
description, the spec.md file. I'm
actually going to read a part of this
because it explained things really well.
OKF is an open human and agent-friendly
format, so it's not just for agents,
humans can use it as well, for
representing knowledge, the metadata,
the context, and the curated insight
that surrounds data and systems. It's
designed to be authored by people,
generated by agents, exchanged across
organizations, which I think is the
really exciting thing, and consumed by
both. They say that the format is
intentionally minimal, and what they
mean by this
they're going to say some words that if
you're not into markdown, cuz I I didn't
know what a YAML front matter is, but
we're going to discover that. It's
actually very, very simple. There's no
schema registry. When I first saw this,
my thought was this is just schema. The
thing is that it's so simple that you
don't need to specifically outline every
specific thing that this is an entity,
that this is
you'll see what I'm talking about. I
think it's important to look at the
terminology that Google gives us. We are
going to be creating what's called a
knowledge bundle. This is a collection
of files. So, OKF is essentially a
directory of directories, and in those
directories are a bunch of markdown
files. Nothing new, but again, the fact
that it's standardized is the important
thing here. I'm fairly certain that
these OKF bundles are things that you
could buy or sell. So, again, like if I
have I have my page on Google algorithm
updates and things that changed with AI
that might be relevant to rankings, I
might sell that as a knowledge bundle
that you can purchase, and then instead
of having to access an MCP for my
uh my website or to use Web MCP, you
would essentially integrate my knowledge
into your system. Each of the markdown
files in these directories represents a
concept. And this is the the concept, no
pun intended, that's hard to understand
here because we're used to as SEOs
uh taking a webpage and saying, "All
right, here is the summary of the
webpage." Instead, each markdown file is
a concept, a single unit of knowledge
within a bundle represented as one
markdown document. So, one website might
produce maybe 50 or maybe 10 or maybe
even more concepts that each would be
their own markdown file. Let's talk
about what this YAML front matter is.
This is the information that is required
in these markdown files. And then after
this information, you can put whatever
you want in the file. So, the you're
going to have the the type, the title,
the description of here's what's in this
file,
uh resource, tags. The tags can be
different topics that are covered and uh
and then a timestamp. All of this will
be really easy. Your agent will do it
for you. It's not something that you
need to really pay a lot of attention
to. What you're probably going to do is
give this spec.md file to your language
model and say, "Create the YAML front
matter for me." Then, after that, are
the instructions or the knowledge or the
data tables or whatever it is that you
want to share on that particular topic.
After the front matter, then there is
the body that has everything else in it.
And there can also be links. And this is
where it's really interesting because
eventually what you're creating is a
knowledge graph of all of your
knowledge, which is really, really
interesting. You can also have citations
that help support a claim in the body.
You don't necessarily have to have that.
Here's an example of how the bundle can
be structured or how it's supposed to be
structured. The index file is where the
every one of these has to have an index
file. This is really interesting, the
log file. A log file can be so that your
agent says, "Oh, I updated this today. I
did this today." And we'll look at
Karpathy's wiki in a minute because it's
really interesting how the role that
your agents play in this. The concept is
the most important thing here. Again, my
concept might be web MCP. And then I
will have a sub I could have
subdirectories. Maybe my concept is MCP
and I have subdirectories for web MCP
and for other things. This is what's
going to take some time is for us to
figure out how to structure these
because every business is going to be
different. Then you can store all these
files in a Git repository. If you don't
know what that is, it's essentially just
uploading it to GitHub, totally free to
do that. You can also store it in a
markdown organizer like Notion or like
Obsidian. Um when this first came out, I
thought that it would be a replacement
for Obsidian. I haven't used Obsidian,
but here's why I said that because I was
considering getting something like
Obsidian. And now I'm like, "Oh,
actually I can just create my own
markdown files. I could create my own
front end to look at those markdown
files. I don't think I'm going to need a
way to store and to organize all the
markdown files." But who knows, I could
be wrong on that. Now, many of the
examples that Google gives us are not
quite what I'm talking about. So, they
talk about using the OKF as a way to get
big query data, especially from GA4,
which I think is really, really
interesting. And it is something that I
want to do. I don't think it's actually
where the power is for most of us who
are are watching this video. And this
example that they give is is it takes a
while, at least it took me a while to
wrap my head around it. So, we have the
stuff that needs to happen, that needs
to be there at the top, which we just
talked about. And then this is the body,
which you don't need to have schema in
your body. You don't need to have
joints. You don't need to have
citations. These are things that this
business, this organization is saying,
"When we look at customer orders, this
is how we organize them." If you didn't
have this, if you were just using rag,
if you were just using a language model
to say, "Get me the information from
BigQuery and organize it," it would
guess in how you are going to organize
things. This way you can say, "This is
how we do it. This is our way of
organizing things." Here's another
example, and I think this is one that
I'm going to use a lot. The type is a
playbook, which is kind of like the
process. And this playbook would be
triggered when a particular thing
happens. So mine might be in my overall
OKR of my knowledge, might be a trigger
that happens uh when somebody talks
about a traffic drop. And then I would
say I have a playbook for diagnosing why
your traffic has dropped. Uh that's the
type of thing. So basically I'm saying
to your agent, "Here's where you go in
my brain to get this information." And
then the interesting thing is the
cross-linking. And this is something
where I think it's going to be very
exciting, where we can start to see the
connections between things that we've
talked about. I'm going to we'll we'll
know more about this. This will be more
interesting when we look at Karpathy's
wiki, because I think this is uh really,
really important to pay attention to. So
let's actually look at Andrej Karpathy's
LLM wiki. This is not exactly what the
OKR is, but I found that reading this
helped me understand the power of what
we can do with these OKRs a lot better.
Karpathy says that uh he talks about the
idea that most people with when we're
using LLMs and you're using documents,
you're thinking of rag, that you're
giving your LLM this massive amount of
context and saying, here's a question,
go find the parts that are relevant in
all of this context in the entirety of
your website, and you're relying on your
agent to do a lot of work. Whereas, his
LLM Wiki is basically saying, like, here
are Here's a Here's a map to where the
important things are in our in our
knowledge. But, here's the part that I'm
really excited about. In his model,
instead of just retrieving from raw
documents at query time, the language
model incrementally builds and maintains
a persistent Wiki. And so, he talks
about when you add a source, it's not
like you're adding a page to a site map
in your website. Instead, your language
model, I think we're all going to have
to create There probably will be tools
that do this for us, but I think the
best ones will be ones that we create
ourselves. We will When you add a
source, the language model doesn't just
index it for later retrieval. It reads
it, extracts the key information, and
integrates it into the existing Wiki,
updating entity pages, revising topic
summaries, noting where new data
contradicts old claims, strengthening or
challenging the evolving synthesis. So,
let's say that today this video goes
into my OKF. The topics that I talk
about get extracted, and each of them
get their own markdown file. Now, let's
say that a couple months from now, I do
another thing about OKF. Maybe I give an
example of how I used it. I did actually
create an OKF of our peppers in our
garden. I'll share that at some point.
So, let's say I share that, then it's
not like that's going to create a whole
new set of concepts. The concept of OKF
has already been discussed, and so what
my language model should do is say, "Oh,
we already have discussed the idea of
OKF. Let's see where I can add to the
body in that information, and then it
might also discover new links that maybe
I have said that OKF is connected to
revenue
that you can can gain from building this
type of thing. Again, more on that in
just a minute. In Karpathy's version, he
says you never or rarely write the wiki
yourself. And this is the part that's
hard to wrap my head around that the
language model is going to write and
maintain all of it. So, once you get it
going, your job is to find new
information. Your job is to learn things
and to maybe write about them, to share
them. It doesn't even have to be your
knowledge. Perhaps when Google publishes
new documentation, I put that into my
OKF and that becomes, you know, the
concepts are Google documentation and
and things like that. He talks about a
few ex- here and I I honestly I think
that it's endless what we could use this
for. I think that anytime you want to
take a bunch of knowledge and you want
to do stuff with agents, this is what
we're going to use. So, let's talk about
where this is going because I think that
this is the new schema. I think it's
funny because I have historically really
struggled with understanding I
understand the importance of some
schema. If you have an e-commerce site
and you have rapidly changing product
prices and things, schema helps the the
web helps Google, helps agents
understand rapidly changing things on
your website. But I didn't like the idea
of mapping out every individual entity
on your site, every piece of schema. I
just didn't understand that. And the
reason is that the web is not our
knowledge is not like that. It's not
natural. This what Google has described
here is a natural way to say, here's
what I learned, now go categorize it
into my brain. And I think that this is
going going evolve over time. Again,
this is just a very early first version.
I do think that we will have two revenue
streams here for most of you who are
watching this video. One is selling this
service to businesses. There will be
tools. I know Saganth Mahanadossan has
created already a tool that will take
your web pages and turn them into an OKF
bundle. However, he is, I think, just
taking each web page. He's not actually
doing the concepts. I'm sure that that
will come. I'm sure there will be many
tools, but I think that there will be
great skill in knowing individually and
understanding a business and
understanding how to organize that
knowledge that is going to be very, very
valuable. So, I would encourage you to
play with this, to create an OKF of just
something. It doesn't have to be your
entire website, but just something so
that you can use it. The next thing is
that this will be valuable to people who
have knowledge to sell. And I you think
that we're going to sell OKF bundles to
each other. I think that kind of blows
my mind at how all of a sudden, I won't
just have an MCP where I can get legal
information to review a document. Like,
I could have my lawyer or the best
lawyer in this area, you know, have his
or her OKF and and have that as part of
my business intelligence. It is really
hard to to wrap my head around that. And
I think and then not only that, it's not
like I'm just having their files and
their static knowledge, but as the law
changes, then what I need to know for my
business knowledge gets updated as well.
But we're going to build this whole
entire network of a brain where those
who have knowledge and expertise in an
area will be very, very valued. Another
question that I saw come up is how will
agents know that you have this OKF? And
I actually think it's going to be in
your LLMs.txt
that there will be a direction to agents
to say that you have an OKF bundle.
We'll see what happens with that. I'm
going to end with this phrase that
Gemini gave me. I've spent endless hours
brainstorming on what OKF means, and
Gemini gave me the phrase semantic
unbaking. And I think that that's just
amazing. I think that we're going to be
able to take our knowledge and instead
of having to work like machines and make
it into something that is machine
readable, we're actually just going to
be able to have these lives where we
learn stuff and we share stuff, and
those who work hard to develop expertise
will be able to be rewarded and we'll be
able to help a lot of people with this.
I hope you found this interesting. I
will be writing more about OKF in my
community, community.maryhines.com,
and uh thanks so much for watching. I
wish you the best of luck with
everything.